<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Misc.</title>
    <description>Sumi - 19 years old. Currently a student pursing a degree in computer science, in London.  Enjoys art and design, and likes to dabble in a lot of things.
</description>
    <link>http://mis-cellaneous.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://mis-cellaneous.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 01:04:26 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 01:04:26 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>India</title>
        <description>&lt;script src=&quot;/scripts/mute.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The benefits of travelling someplace new and unfamiliar is well known. We are all familiar with the pleasures of travelling and also with the heart ache that comes with leaving a place you have just begun to love. &lt;/p&gt;
	
	&lt;p&gt;This summer, I went to India. The trip was out of this world, but just like with any other pleasant and wonderful things in life, I have been struggling to properly express what I loved about it. Even as I try to write this blog, I stare at the blinking cursor trying my best to form sentences.&lt;/p&gt;
	
	&lt;p&gt;I went to Bangalore for two and a half months on an internship programme. I met a lot of wonderful people there. It was my first time in India, but it felt very familiar when I got there. The bright-coloured houses, the insane traffic, the constant noise pollution, the smell of rubber and dust, and the cheerful locals - it all reminded me of Nepal. &lt;/p&gt;
	
	&lt;p&gt;India is an interesting place to travel with new people. There is always a surprise waiting for you at every turn. The heat, the smells, the sounds - it is a blast to all your senses, yet there is something very relaxed about India. It is the only place where I have seen two people have a casual conversation with each other while driving side by side at 35mph.&lt;/p&gt;
	
	&lt;p&gt;Whether you are just looking to hang out with friends and grab a couple pints of beer, or visit an ancient temple way on the top of a hill, or just want to stroll through some exquisite maze of alleyways, - there is always something for everyone. &lt;/p&gt;
	
	&lt;p&gt;I can list the names of all the places I visited in India. Places like Goa (Oh Goa..), Mumbai, Hampi, New Delhi, Agra, Bangalore and Coorg. But, a travel guide will provide more accurate and enticing descriptions of these places than I can. So, instead, I can share with you some of things that I learnt there. &lt;/p&gt;
	
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Let your bank know about your travels, so that they don't mistake you for a fraud. (Yep, it happened to me)
		&lt;li&gt;India is really big. Seriously, like... really big. 
		&lt;li&gt;If you are planning on packing a bikini, you might want to think again.
		&lt;li&gt;You can easily befriend a cab driver in India.
		&lt;li&gt;Locals love seeing foreigners immersing themselves in Indian culture, like wearing a traditional outfit, or eating their local food. Some also find it hysterical when you can't handle spicy food.
		&lt;li&gt;Everyone speaks english!
		&lt;li&gt;You find yourself converting currencies every time you spend money.
		&lt;li&gt;Get used to people staring at you.
		&lt;li&gt;If you are planning to visit the Taj Mahal, go at sunrise. There will only be a handful of people, and the white marble which the Taj is built out of picks up this orangish hue from the morning sun. The sight is breathtaking.
		&lt;li&gt;Yes, you did pay the shopkeeper waaayy too much for that tiny elephant statue.
		&lt;li&gt;People are generally helpful and happy to talk to tourists.
		&lt;li&gt;All businesses close super early.
		&lt;li&gt;Crossing the road is a pain.
		&lt;li&gt;Bars in India play a lot of old school rock music like Green Day, SUM 41, Simple Plan, etc. This was a surprise since bars in England play only pop music.
		&lt;li&gt;You will catch yourself doing a funny head bobbing action (used as a gesture of agreement) which you probably picked up from the locals.
		&lt;li&gt;Coconut trees here. Coconut trees there. Coconut trees everywhere!
		&lt;li&gt;Vegetarians definitely have it better than non-vegetarians in India. Also, it is very hard to find places that serve beef.
		&lt;li&gt;Damn it, I want another elephant statue.
	&amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt;
	&lt;p&gt;I had one of the best times of my life there, and my only regret is that I didn't travel as many places as I wanted. Of course, when you're there it feels like you are never going to leave. I will be patiently waiting till my next trip to India, and till then, I can always dive into these wonderful memories and relive the same ineffable joys I felt when I was in India.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;P.S To play the video just scroll up and click on the blank space&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 20:10:01 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://mis-cellaneous.com/blog/2016/08/10/India</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mis-cellaneous.com/blog/2016/08/10/India</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Stopping You?</title>
        <description>&lt;script src=&quot;/scripts/mute.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been in a situation where you are aware of all the things you need to do, but there is this fog of uncertainty surrounding you that stops you from moving forward or takes you longer to accomplish your goals? Maybe you really need to finish that homework assignment or maybe you want to start working out, and you still don't have the energy to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;By this point you might just shrug it off and say, &quot;I'm just too lazy to do it.&quot; However, most of the time, it's because you've simply not paid much attention to the actual problem that is mentally and physically stopping you. You are never truly aware of it until you pull yourself out of the hypnotic trance of everyday life. Sounds trivial, right? But, how many of us actually make a conscious effort to stop and make sense of our situation?&lt;/p&gt;
	
	&lt;p&gt;Don't get me wrong. I am not a psychologist. This is just a small observation. We all struggle with this. But what I do know is a tiny solution which is in no way mind blowing or surprising. You probably subconsciously do this every time you have to a make a decision. But, in this case, you can see it physically.&lt;/p&gt;
	
	&lt;p&gt;So, take a paper and a pen.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;b&gt;Step 1.&lt;/b&gt; Write down what you need to do.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;b&gt;Step 2.&lt;/b&gt; Draw one or mulitple arrows downwards to point to the reasons why you are unable to do the task.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;b&gt;Step 3.&lt;/b&gt; For each problems/reason, can you find a way to fix it? If yes, then your current problem is solved! Write down the solution and execute the right action. Move to the next reason. If not, repeat  step 2 and step 3 until your answer is yes and you have found a problem that is solvable.&lt;/p&gt; 
	
	&lt;p&gt;After that, the problem will neatly fold itself up the steps since that now every problem is solvable. As an example just resume the video!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- [jekyll-docs]: http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home
[jekyll-gh]:   https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll
[jekyll-talk]: https://talk.jekyllrb.com/ --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 20:10:01 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://mis-cellaneous.com/blog/2016/08/09/what-is-stopping-you</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mis-cellaneous.com/blog/2016/08/09/what-is-stopping-you</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NEW YEAR, NEW BLOG</title>
        <description>&lt;script src=&quot;/scripts/mute.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;This was one of the journeys I took from Kathmandu to a small and almost isolated village called Phidim last summer in Nepal. I was inside a hefty and crowded bus, (only 20 mins into the 24 hour long ride) when I took this footage. Yup. 24 hours. The reason why it takes so long to travel to anywhere in Nepal by road is because of all the hills! The journey takes even longer if there is a landslide or a road accident involved. So basically, you're stuck inside a metal container along with a bunch of anxious strangers for 24 hours, except for the occasional toilet and meal breaks. By no means is this a fancy bus designed to alleviate your discomfort. Open windows are your air conditioner, a bottle of water and a bag of peanuts is all the food you get and unapologetically cheesy songs blare out of speakers (which is why the muted video).&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;At the end of this long journey, I was to meet with some friends and family members whom I had only seen once on a previous trip to Phidim when I was 10. What happened when I got to Phidim and how my perspective had changed after almost 10 years is a completely different topic for another blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Speaking of blog posts, this is my new blog for a new year. This will hopefully be a place where I can share some ideas, talk about what's on my mind and reach out to awesome people like you guys. I'll put up a video with my post, just like I've done for this one, as a visual tidbit. My posts will be miscellaneous, as you probably have already guessed, since I am an amateur of a lot of things and an expert of nothing, yet. The look of website will change until I have figured out a layout that I am happy with.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;I still have to fix some of the tiny bugs like adjusting the fonts and texts with different screen sizes, which will be done in no time. I'll try my best to post frequently. Stay tuned for more miscellaneous!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- [jekyll-docs]: http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home
[jekyll-gh]:   https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll
[jekyll-talk]: https://talk.jekyllrb.com/ --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 20:10:01 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://mis-cellaneous.com/blog/2016/08/08/welcome-to-jekyll</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mis-cellaneous.com/blog/2016/08/08/welcome-to-jekyll</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
